https://www.californianorth.com/privacy-policy/

Site Information
Loading... Please wait...
California North Skincare & Fragrance
Health-Conscious. Eco-Friendly. Cruelty-Free. Made in USA.
Free Shipping to Lower 48 States on Orders Over $50.
Join Thousands of Happy Subscribers
10% Off Your First Order!
(Click to Sign Up)
Samples
At California North your privacy is important to us. We do not use your information for any purpose other than providing the sale of our goods to you online, and subsequent email advertising that you consent to by choosing to sign up for email news on our website form. Please read below for detailed information regarding our operations.
What Data is Collected and Processed at CN
When you visit our website, we automatically collect certain information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. As you interact with our website, we collect information about web pages or products that you view, the websites or search terms that referred you to our website, and information about how you engage with our website.
When you make a purchase we collect information from you, including your name, billing address, shipping address, payment information, email address, and phone number. We only collect and process information about you as necessary to deliver our goods, and research interests such as data analytics to improve our services.
How We Use Your Data To Provide Services
The data we collect from customers is used to fulfill orders placed through our website, which includes the processing of payment information, preparing orders for shipment, and providing order confirmations and other order related communication.
Data from your visit(s) is used to improve and optimize your customer experience, to screen for potential risk and fraud, to provide the most relevant email communications to you (should you choose to sign up), and to assess the success of our current marketing and advertising campaigns. This data is used for no other purpose except to provide services to you as a valued customer.
Consent and Your Rights
By accessing our website and providing data to complete a transaction or to receive email communication from us, you have provided your consent for our use and collection of your data.
If you no longer wish that we utilize your data, you may withdraw your consent by contacting us at service@californianorth.com to request your data deleted or via mail at: California North, 301 Wilson Ave Novato, CA 94947
.
Retention of Data
By submitting your data through our website, you agree to the transfer, storing and processing of your data, which, depending on the use of third party services, may be processed, transferred and stored outside of the country where you reside. When you place an order through our website, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.
European and International Visitors
California North is located in the United States and does not target or engage European residents in marketing or sell directly to them. Our business at californianorth.com is in service of our domestic market in the USA only. If you are a European resident and visit our site, you acknowledge that the above retention of data apples.
You have the right to access personal information we may hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. If you would like to exercise this right, please contact us at service@californianorth.com or via mail at: California North, 301 Wilson Ave Novato, CA
94947 USA.
European residents who believe any concerns regarding their data have not been adequately addressed by us may file an inquiry with the supervisory authority of their particular Member State, as defined under GDPR.
*Please note that as a U.S. company, not engaged in serving or targeting European visitors, our obligation to comply with any formal requests may not be deemed legally necessary in our jurisdiction. We will review all requests and act accordingly at our discretion.
As a courtesy we direct visitors to our USA website that may be in the Europe market to the independent distributor which serves their region. California North does not own or operate any websites serving Europe. If you are a European customer, please visit the independent distributor serving your region at https://www.californianorth.eu.
Website Cookies
A cookie is a small text file that is stored in your web browser that allows our website to recognize you and your website preferences. Cookies may be used to enable certain site features and to provide data analytics. You may set your cookie preferences in your browser settings as you see fit.
You may also opt out of targeted advertising through the following services directly:
Facebook - https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads
Google - https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous
Digital Advertising Alliance - http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/
National Advertising Initiative - http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/
Bigcommerce
Our store is hosted on Bigcommerce, a well respected leader in online e-commerce. They provide the storefront which allows us to sell our products to you. Your data is stored via Bigcommerce on secure infrastructure with dedicated resources to ongoing security and management.
We do not store any detailed payment or financial information directly on our website as we do not accept direct payments through the platform. All payment information is processed by our third party industry-leading payment processors, Authorize.net and Pay Pal.
These vendors collect and process information required to complete your transaction on our website and have detailed privacy policies that we recommend you read. Security is of the utmost importance and each payment gateway is recognized as a leader in online payments.
Bigcommerce Privacy Policy: https://www.bigcommerce.com/privacy/
Authorize.net Privacy Policy: https://www.authorize.net/company/privacy/
PayPal Privacy Policy: https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full
Third Party Services
Our third party providers will only collect, use and disclose your data to the extent necessary to allow them to perform the services they provide to us.
Providers such as payment gateways and other payment transaction processors, have their own privacy policies in respect to the information we are required to provide to them for your transactions. We recommend that you read their privacy policies so you can understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these providers.
Providers may also be located in and/or have facilities that are located in a different jurisdiction than you or us. If you elect to proceed with a transaction that involves the services of a third party provider, your information may become subject to the laws of the jurisdiction in which that service provider or its infrastructure is located.
Once you leave our website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no longer governed by this privacy policy.
Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, customers living in the State of California can request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.
Privacy policies of our third party vendors:
Bigcommerce Privacy Policy: https://www.bigcommerce.com/privacy/
PayPal Privacy Policy: https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full
Google Analytics Privacy Policy: https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en
Campaign Monitor: https://www.campaignmonitor.com/policies/
Disclosure of Your Personal Data
We will not sell, trade, rent or otherwise disclose your data to third parties for illicit purposes. No exceptions, ever. We take your trust in us very seriously and we only aim to use your data in a manner as required to directly provide the sale of our goods to you.
We will only disclose data if it is required by law enforcement or judicial authorities, or to cooperate with a law enforcement investigation. If we have a good faith belief that we are required or permitted to do so by law or legal process. To protect our rights, reputation, property, or the safety of us or others. To defend or enforce our rights or your obligations. If the disclosure is required by mandatory professional standards. To a third party with your prior consent. If we are under a duty to disclose or share your data in order to enforce or apply any contracts or agreements that may exist between you and us, including this privacy policy and our terms of service found on our website. If we are required to exchange information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and risk reduction.
We obtain support through trusted, experienced, long-term, third party service providers to maintain our website, offer creative marketing, provide our products for sale, process customer orders, and deliver orders. For example, we must release your credit card information to the card issuing bank to confirm payment for products and services purchased on our website.
We must provide your address to our shipping partner to deliver your order.
In the event California North sells its assets to an acquiring entity or merges with another entity, we reserve the right to provide your data to the acquiring or surviving entity for continuity of service.
Data Security
To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.
There are security and privacy limitations of the internet that are beyond our control; the security, integrity, and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through our website cannot be guaranteed and we shall have no liability to you or any third party for loss, misuse, disclosure or alteration of such information; and any such information and data may be viewed or tampered with in transit by a third party.
In the unlikely event that we believe the security of your data in our control may have been compromised, we will make every attempt to notify you. To the extent you have provided us with your email address, we may notify you by email and you agree to our use of email as a means of such notification.
If you prefer for us to use another method to notify you in this situation, please contact us at service@californianorth.com with the alternative contact information you wish to be used.
Do Not Track Disclosure
Certain websites provide  “do not track” features that allow users to instruct a website not to track their activity, each to a varying degree. California North does not currently respond to those signals; however, our marketing partners may be members of the Network Advertising Initiative or the Digital Advertising Alliance, which have agreed to honor consumers’ opt-out preferences submitted through those organizations’ websites.
To learn more about your choices regarding this type of data collection or to opt out of interest-based advertising by members of the NAI or the DAA, please visit the choices websites of the NAI and DAA at https://www.aboutads.info. You also may locate Google Analytics’ currently available opt-outs for the web here: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/.
Age of Consent
We are not a site targeted at children or those under the age of 18. By using our website, you represent that you are at least the age of majority in your country, state or province of residence, or that you are the age of majority in your country, state or province of residence and you have given us your consent to allow any of your minor dependents to use our website.
Privacy Policy Updates
We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on our website. If we make material changes to this privacy policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.
How to Reach Us
If you would like to access, correct, amend or delete any personal information we have about you, register a complaint, or simply want more information please email us at
service@californianorth.com or via mail at
California North
301 Wilson Avenue
Novato, CA
USA
.
We appreciate your business and trust in us. Please rest assured that we are always taking privacy very seriously.
Join Thousands of Happy Customers!
10% Off Your First OrderExclusive Subscriber Only Sale Events
Subscribe and we'll send you an instant 10% off coupon to use on your first order!Plus enjoy the latest product news and subscriber exclusive sale events.
U.S. Orders Only. Limit one first time use code per customer. Cannot be combined with other codes and not applicable mark downs, sale items and product samples. We will only email when we've got something really special to share. We hate junkmail too!
Email
Subscribe
Navigate
Shop
About Us
Customer Service
Wholesale
Covid-19 Info
